Alicia N. Gorton

apersigehl@gmail.com (217) 377-7697 Sacramento, CA

Work Portfolio: aliciagorton.com Code Repository: github.com/aliciagorton LinkedIn: linkedIn: linkedIn.com/in/alicia-gorton

I am a recent graduate of a Full Stack Web Developer bootcamp taught by UC Davis, with a focus on creating web applications using MongoDB, Express, React and Node.js (MERN). I enjoy working in collaborative environments and taking on challenging projects.

I am deeply empathetic towards others, demonstrated by my extensive background in nursing, psychology and behavioral therapy with children diagnosed with autism. Those experiences have enabled a strong sense of what others are needing when they can't always articulate well enough for themselves. I wish to use those skills to build better software experiences for end users, as well as help my team and workmates understand all dimensions of our projects.

Technical Skills

React
MongoDB
MySQL
Node.js
Express
JavaScript
Bootstrap

BOOTCAMP PROJECTS

Kuma Code: bit.ly/3mmBBDA Live: bit.ly/3mkn6A1

My biggest takeaways with this project was understanding how user credentials, web sessions and relational databases work, though I really enjoyed user interface design and working on the frontend. Kuma is an application that allows people to create profiles for their pets and compare traits with other pets to find playdates for them while also meeting new people with similar interests. Built using Sequelize, Passport, Express, Node.js, Handlebars, MySQL, Bootstrap, and JavaScript.

Chuck Norris Fan Page Code: bit.ly/3jtaVik Live: bit.ly/34rx9wV

My role in this project was to make our APIs functional and create event listeners to react to user interactivity. I learned a lot about how the DOM works and making fetch requests with APIs. The "Fan Page" design is intended to be a retro throwback, reminiscent of early web experiences. Built using two server-side APIs, a third-party API, Javascript, and Bulma.

Eat-Da-Burger Code: bit.ly/3dRrDa8 Live: bit.ly/2J4LozF

This was my first deployed full-stack application. Users click on various buttons to build a burger from a menu list, or create something totally unique for them to devour. My biggest takeaways were learning how to interact with databases and deploying applications to Heroku. Additional skills required using MySQL, Node.js, Express, and Handlebars.

Employee Time Tracker Code: bit.ly/35xcMOo Live: bit.ly/35xcMOo Live: bit.ly/3kvflBa

This assignment is an application that allows the user to interact with data related to specific employees. This program uses MySQL database to store information on the user and when the user chooses an option the corresponding tables will appear to use. Built using MySQL, Node.js, Express, and JavaScript.

Express Note Taker Code: bit.ly/3jsXu27 Live: bit.ly/35xXEAa

In this assignment, the user can create an application that can be used to write, save, and delete notes. It uses an Express backend and saves and retrieves note data from a JSON file. Built using MySQL, Express, Node.js, and JavaScript.

EDUCATION

Full-Stack Web Development CertificateUniversity of California at DavisGraduated 2020Bachelor of Science in PsychologyUniversity of Illinois at Urbana ChampaignGraduated 2017Licensed Practical NurseParkland CollegeGraduated 2012

PREVIOUS WORK EXPERIENCE

Registered Behavioral Technician (RBT) *Maxim Healthcare Services - Sacramento, CA ... October 2019 to August 2020*

Provided direct ABA therapy to children with autism. Worked in multiple environments; including homes and in schools. Responsible for implementation of the plan of care and a strong relationship with families involved.

Registered Behavioral Technician (RBT) Intercare Therapy Inc. - Sacramento, CA ... June 2019 to October 2019

Delivered direct ABA therapy to children with autism. Worked in multiple environments; including homes and in community settings. Responsible for implementation of the plan of care and a strong relationship with families involved.

Behavior Technician Comprehensive Early Autism Services - Chicago, IL ... May 2018 to May 2019

Executed direct ABA therapy to children with autism. Worked in multiple environments; including homes and in schools. Responsible for implementation of the plan of care and a strong relationship with families involved.

Undergraduate Research AssistantLanguage Acquisition Lab - Urbana, IL ... June 2016 to May 2017

Helped to design materials for experiments. Tested toddlers, preschoolers, and adults in experiments. Responsible for transcription, coding of children's speech, and coding visual fixations from video recordings.

Licensed Practical Nurse Carle Foundation Hospital - Urbana, IL ... July 2013 to June 2014

Delivered nursing care to patients in outpatient procedures. Evaluations, interventions and modification of the plan of care with each patient. Responsible for scheduling and instructing patients for procedures.

Licensed Practical Nurse Heartland Health Care Center - Champaign, IL ... August 2012 to June 2013

Provided skilled nursing care for assisted living, post-acute medical, rehabilitation and hospice care. Direct care was my primary responsibility, along with supervisor responsibility of nursing assistants.

CERTIFICATIONS AND LICENSES

Full-Stack Web Development Licensed Practical Nurse (IL) Registered Behavioral Technician (CA)
University of California at Davis August 2012 to January 2017 September 2019 to Present
June 2020 to December 2020 License Number: 043115413 Certification Number: RBT 19-98636